Barskov Nikita

Data Engineer at Maxifier. Master Degree Student at Samara University.

P Samara, Russia

J +7(927)657-16-10

github.com/nikitabarskov

in linkedin.com/in/nikitabarskov

◀ t.me/nikitabarskov

Professional Summary

I am a data engineer, an enthusiast for developing intelligent and modern applications that improve the quality of using and presenting data. I've got 2 years experience with implementing ETL with frameworks such as Apache Spark, Apache Hadoop, Apache Mesos. I'm well known in Python data analysis libraries, mathematical packages, and visualization tools.

I'm a bachelor of applied mathematics and physics with close to excellent average score (4.75/5.0). All mathematical and software engineer exercises have done with excellent score. My academic mathematical background allows me to take advantages of statistic, calculus and algebra methods for transforming data as I need and extracting necessary information for my work and needs.

Now, I'm a student at Samara University with an excellent (5.0/5.0 at the moment) average score. Masters programme «Data Mining and Quality Assurance» contains courses about software lifecycle, testing, basic business analysis knowledge and fundamentals of machine learning. My Master's thesis theme is «Forecasting users interacting with advertising content on sites» and it absolutely relates with my current job specific.

Experience

Maxifier, Samara, Russia

Intern April 2017 – June 2017

Working on batch processing project in Maxifier as Intern.

Stack: Java, Guice, PostgreSQL, Spark, Hadoop, Aurora, Bazel, GitLab Cl.

Data Engineer June 2017 - Present

Developing the application for forecasting users interactions with advertising content and its evaluation. Stack: Python/Scala, Spark, Hadoop, Mesos, Docker, MySQL, Akka, Slick, SciPy, Maven, GitHub.

Education

Samara University, Samara Russia

Master Degree Student Data Analysis and Quality Assurance, Average Point 5.0 **Bachelor of Science**

Applied Mathematics and Physics, Average Point 4.75

September 2017 - Present

Sep 2013 - June 2017

Skills

Personal: rational, responsible, sociable

Base Skills: advanced knowledge in mathematics and application of these methods to ETL

Natural Languages: Russian (native), English (intermediate)

Programming Languages: Python 3 (intermediate knowledge for writing batch processing jobs and data

science), Scala, Java (regular knowledge for writing services and batch processing jobs)

Frameworks and libraries: Apache Spark, Apache Hadoop, Apache Mesos, Docker, Scipy(Pandas, Numpy,

Matplotlib), Scikit-learn, Akka, Slick

Build Tools and VCS: Maven, Bazel, Git, Gitlab Cl, Github

Others: knowledge in process cycle of Software Application Development, methodologies, QA, Bussiness and System Analytics